Jan Schjønning

Senior java developer

Birgits Alle 9, 5250 Odense SV

Mobil: 40344403

LinkedIn

jan.schjoenning@gmail.com



Resume

Competent and experienced developer with wide project experience from development over architecture to techlead. Expert in Java and quick to get into new technologies and domains, have experience with offshore development, and adhere to methods and processes in several different projects.

Jan has many years of experience in designing and developing software for the telecommunications and media industry focusing on industry standards, flexibility and stability. Jan has experience in user interface design and development, including Android (such as TV Guide (1,6M users)) - but primarily as a study for design of APIs and services.

Good to use the broad experience to get a quick overview of all technical aspects of a project in a business domain. This means that Jan works very purposefully and pragmatically in the daily life and focuses on quality with regard to project delivery.

Jan has primarily worked in agile development environment for the last 5 years, and has experience with Scrum and related methods.

Actual toolbox

- 1. Java (8)
- 2. Rest JAX-RS / Jersey 2
- 3. Apache Camel
- 4. Json/XML/XSLT
- 5. Jetty
- 6. PostgreSQL / MySQL / Elasticsearch
- 7. Github
- 8. Gradle/maven
- 9. Docker, Rancher
- 10. Eclipse, IntelliJ
- 11. Jira, Confluence

Working experience

TV 2 *Mobile Architect* **2013 til 2017** Design and implementing content services til mobile devices. **Development environment** Java, jetty, Postgres MySQL, linux, Docker, Rancher, Apache Camel, Elasticsearch.

Capgemini Managing Consultant 2006 to 2013 Enterprise/Solution-architect within a ApplicationManagement contract with TDC. A rightshore contract, which was gradually transited to the back office in Inden - ending with a split of approx. 10/90. Last major task was 1st part of an EA program, implementation of a SOA architecture - with product hub, order management, etc. Resigned in connection with assignment at TV 2 and closure of the office in Odense. Development environment Java, Weblogic, Oracle, OSM.

TDC /T Architect 1999 to 2006

Maintenance and optimize MobileSystem for increased traffic volumes. Migration to new platform. Solution Architect for Integration. Outsourced to Capgemini. **Development environment** Cobol, Java, Weblogic, Oracle, Tandem NonstopSQL).

KMD Database administrator **1998** to **1999** Primarily employed for designing and implementing decentralized databases for KMD's first Cool Gen-based System for Environment (Registration of Environment-Impacted Sites). Secondary DB2 administration. Resigned due to offer from TDC.**Development environment** SQL Server, Oracle, Cool gen, DB2.

Teledanmark EDB *Database administrator* **1994 to 1998** Insourcing and Maintenance of Complete Customer, Order, Billing / Traffic System. Resigned due to discontinuation of new development activities. **Development environment** Digital RDB, ACMS, Pascal, Cobol, Tandem NonstopSQL).

Fyns Telefon *Database administrator* **1989 to 1994** Buisiness transferred too Teledanmark. **Development environment** Digital RDB, ACMS, Pascal).

ISS Data *IRM - Information Resource Manager* **1987 to 1989** Resigned due to family increase. **Development environment** DB2, Cobol, CSP, CICS.

Carlsberg *Programmer* **1984 to 1987** Resigned due to the desire for focus on databases. **Development environment** Cobol, CSP, CICS, DB2.

JDC Data *Programmer* **1982 to 1984** Development and maintenance of accounting systems on central NCR and decentralized microcomputer. **Development environment** Cobol, PL1.

Fyns Data Service/JDC Data Operator - teamlead 1980 to 1982

Elias B. Muus Computer assistent 1979 to 1980

Jydske Dragonregiment Private 1978 to 1978

Fyns Data Service Operator 1976 to 1978

Projects

- EPG Design and implementation of shared EPG services across clients in TV-Anytime format. Data base forthe popular TV guide tvtid, press releases and streaming service PLAY. Development environment Java, Maven, PostgreSQL, Jetty, Apache Camel, Elasticsearch, Docker, Rancher.
- Sportdata Design and implementation of REST services to support the TV 2
 Sportcenter app for mobile devices. Development environment Java, Gradle,
 PostgreSQL, Jetty.
- OVP Design and implementation of platform to support PLAY streaming service.
 Principles for microservices were used **Development environment** Java,
 PostgreSQL, Jetty, Docker, Rancher.
- Content management Design and implementation of service component for all written content. Search, etc. Supported by Replication to ElasticSearch.
 Development environment Java, Postgres, jetty, ElasticSearch.
- **ESB** Choice of ESBenvironment and subsequent implementation of poc. The project stopped due to funding and achieved only partially in goals. Experience gained with Camel. **Development environment** WSO2, ServiceMix/Camel, Mulesoft.
- TvTID Design and implementation of REST services to support TV 2 TV guide (tvtid) for mobile devices. Developed tvtid for Android devices (200k users). Development environment Android, Java, MySQL,jetty.
- Push motor Design and implementation for push motor for mobile devices, to support current news - breaking news. Everyday, 1-5 news is sent to more than 1M users. In connection with the project, JAX-RS (Jersey) was selected as the primary framework for REST api development. Development environment Java, MySQL,jetty.
- **Drupal TvTid** Implementing fake nodes for content management. **Development environment** PHP, Drupal.
- Retailmanagement Solution Architect on Implementing Product Hub, Order
 Management, Service interface for CRM System. Large 2 year rightshore project,
 primarily with Indian employees. Design of complete product structure (SID model)
 covering all TDC's products. "Configuration" of OSM ie design of order
 management workflow with integration to TDC Mobile and landline systems. The
 project was the first part of a major EA project that would enable all types of
 customers to be operated on the same platform. The project involved on site
 presence in India. Development environment Java, Oracle Osm, weblogic samt
 databaser, XML/XSLT.

Outsourcing

Training and transfer of all integration to the Indian back office, which included 5

weeks stay in India. **Development environment** Java, Oracle weblogic samt databaser.

 AKS Aktiv Kredit Sikring Design and implementation of services based on replicated credit data from RKI. Development environment Java, Oracle weblogic samt databaser.

Rating dokumentation

Implementation and customization of Amdocs Ensemble rating flow in order to document money flow. **Development environment** Cobol, bash, Oracle Db.

- Udskiftning af provisioneringssystem Replacement of TDC Mobile Provisioning Platform to Comtel InstantLink. The platform is integration between CRM systems and telecommunications equipment. Solution Manager in 3-man team, who designed new configuration, comprehensive systematic parallel test with subsequent troublefree production. Development environment Cobol, TandemSQL.
- B2B api-gateway Design and implementation of api for use by all TDC service providers. Service interface for more than 2m subscribers. Development environment Java, SOAP, Oracle weblogic samt databaser.
- Amdocs api Design and implementation of service interface to Amdocs Ensemble system. Development environment Java, Oracle weblogic.
- NABS Migrering Primarily employed design and implementation of product / installment conversion rules from proprietary system to Amdoc's Ensemble system.
 TDC's management named it Denmark's largest and most successful migration project. Development environment Cobol, Oracle, PL/SQL.
- Yousee CRM&billing Copying, provisioning and commissioning of the entire TDC mobile CRM and billing platform for Yousee. Teamlead for 3 man team. Development environment Cobol, TandemSQL.

FKS

Design and implementaion of solution for registration and automatic capble pipeline creation - covering both subscriber and mid-range cable networks. Fyns Telefon was the first fully digital network in Denmark and thus the first to introduce the automation. **Development environment** Digital RDB, Pascal, ACMS.

- **FIKS** Design and implemenation of complete data architecture for Fyns Phone's integrated CRM and billing system more than 1k tables. Only db administrator. Fyns Telefon was the first telecommunications company with full billing specification. The solution covered both mobile and landline subscriptions. **Development environment** Digital RDB.
- MB Design and implimentation of solution for recording origin and mixing of brew.
 Development environment CSP, CICS, DB2.
- Uddannelsessystem Design and implemenation of solution for registration and follow-up on courses. Carlsberg's first DB2 solution. Development environment

CSP, DB2.

• **H1** Design and implement of solution for data collection from production environment on decentralized computers **Development environment** COBOL, HoneywellBull.

Education

• "EDB assistent" - enkeltfag 1979 to 1982 Tietgenskolen, Aftenskolen, Odense

Courses

- Relationsdatabaser 1984 og 1989 Cood & Date/v Date, København
- Amdocs Ensample development 2000 Amdocs, TDC kursuslokaler, Odense
- Java certificering 2005 Selvstudie, Odense
- SOA arkitektur 2006 Capgemini, Univercity, Paris
- Enterprise arkitektur 2007 Capgemini, Univercity, Paris
- SCRUM master 2010 Jeff Sutherland (Inventor of Scrum), Trifork, Århus
- Android udvikling 2014 Super Users, Hillerød
- Architecting on AWS 2017 Nordcloud, København

Private status

 Married to Kirsten (Pedagogue) and father of Amalie (28, Cand. Art.), Kristian (26, Stud. IT Diploma Engineer) and Anders (19, Prescribed)